A coroutine can be though of as being a function
コルーチンは一定間隔で実行される関数のようなものと
that is executed in intervals.
考えることができます
These functions work with special yield statements
これら関数は  関数に対してコードの実行を返す
which return the code execution out of the function.
特別な yield 文とともに使われます
Then when the function continues
そして関数が処理を続行していくと
execution begins again right from where it left off.
前回の途中から実行が再開されます
Let's take a look at an example coroutine.
まずはコルーチンのサンプルを見てみましょう
To start let's take a look at the coroutine
まずはコルーチン自体に注目してみます
itself which we have called MyCoroutine.
ここでは MyCoroutine という名前です
The first thing to notice is it's return type.
まず目につくのが戻り値の型
IEnumerator.
IEnumerator です
This means that the function can return anything
これは関数が IEnumerator インターフェイスを実装するものであれば
which implements the IEnumerator interface.
何でも返せるということを意味します
There is more to returning from a coroutine than
コルーチンから返されるものは通常よりも多岐にわたりますが
usual however as you will see in a moment.
それは後々見ていくこととしましょう
Next we see that it takes a transform as a parameter.
次にパラメーターとして Transform が指定され
We are then starting a While Loop which will continue
そして while ループが始まり
until the distance between the object and the target
これがオブジェクトと target の距離が 0.05 未満になるまで
is less than 0.05.
繰り返されます
Within the loop we are firstly lerping the
このループ内ではまずオブジェクトの位置を
object's position between itself and the target position.
自身と target の位置の間で 線形補間（Lerp）しています
Then we have the line yield return null.
続いて yield return null; という行があります
This is what allows a coroutine to work the way it does.
ここがコルーチンの仕事を可能にしている部分です
What this means is that when this line of code is
具体的に何が起こるかというと まず
executed it will yield execution of
この行が実行されると関数が実行され
the function and return a null IEnumerator.
IEnumerator に null が返されます
The code will resume at this point at the
そして戻り値で指定されたタイミングで
time dictated by the return value.
コードの実行が再開されます
Since the return value is null, that means
戻り値は null なので
the coroutine will resume after the next update.
コルーチンは次のアップデート後に再開されるのです
Since the coroutine will resume at the end of the loop
そしてコルーチンがループの最後に再開されるため
the loop condition will then be reevaluated.
ループ条件が再判定されます
If the transform has not reached the target yet
transform が target に到達していない場合は
it will lerp closer to the target and again
ターゲットに近づくよう線形補間（Lerp）が行われ
it will yield until the next update.
次回アップデートまで yield が実行されます
Once the loop condition is no longer evaluated
最終的にループ条件の判定が true でなくなると
to true the loop will exit and the coroutine
ループ処理が終了してコルーチンが
will print 'reached the target'
コンソールに「reached the target」（ターゲットに到達）と
to the console.
プリントします
At that point the coroutine will yield again
この時コルーチンは yield を実行しますが
but this time it's returning an instance of the
この場合の戻り値は WaitForSeconds クラスの
WaitForSeconds class.
インスタンスとなります
The constructor is called using the new keyword
そして新しいキーワードでコンストラクターが呼び出されます
and in this case we're parsing in 3
この例ではパラメーターとして 3 が
as a parameter.
パースされます
Predictably the result of returning an
そして WaitForSeconds クラスのインスタンスを
instance of the WaitForSeconds class is that
返した後は  ご想像の通り
the code will continue execution after the
指定された秒数後に
given number of seconds.
コードが続行されます
After 3 seconds the words 'MyCoroutine is now finished'
この場合 3 秒後に「MyCoroutine is now finished」（MyCoroutine が終了しました）
are printed to the console.
がコンソールに表示されます
At that point we've reached the end of the coroutine
これでコルーチンの終わりに達し
and execution will finish.
実行は終了されます
Now let's take a look at how to call a coroutine.
さて それではコルーチンの呼び出し方について見ていきましょう
We do so simply with the StartCoroutine function.
これには単純に StartCoroutine 関数を使います
It takes a parameter of either a coroutine call
この関数はパラメーターとして コルーチンのコールまたは
or a string of the coroutine's name.
コルーチン名の文字列をひとつ取ります
The former call is the one we've shown here
前者のコールを用いた方法が先ほど見たやり方で
and is more advisable, however
推奨の方法でもありますが
if you use a call with a name string
コルーチン名の文字列で呼び出した場合は
then you can also call StopCoroutine
StopCoroutine を使って
to halt it prematurely.
完全に停止させることができます
Now let's see this coroutine in action.
それではコルーチンが動作するところを見てみましょう
We have attached the coroutine script to this little
ここではコルーチンスクリプトをかわいいロボに
robot and we've created a target object.
アタッチして さらに target オブジェクトを作成しました
When the scene is run the robot moves
シーンが実行されるとロボが target に向かって
towards it's target, and when the robot
移動していき ロボが target に
reaches it's target the console displays the message.
到達すると  コンソールにメッセージが表示されます
Then, 3 seconds later, the coroutine
そしてメッセージから 3 秒後
finishes with the second message.
2 つめのメッセージと共にコルーチンが終了します
Note that we have created movement without
この例では Update を使ったり タイマーを作ったりせずに
using Update or creating any timers.
移動を作成していることにお気づきでしょうか?
This is really excellent and makes our
これはとても優れた方法で
code more efficient.
コードも効率的になります
However a real strength of coroutines is
しかしコルーチンの本当の強みは
when they are combined with properties.
プロパティと組み合わせた時に発揮されます
Let's take a look at an example of that.
例を見てみましょう
In this scene we have another robot.
このシーンでも ふたたびロボを使います
The robot has a PropertiesAndCoroutines
このロボには  PropertiesAndCoroutines という
script on it.
スクリプトがアタッチされています
We also have a script called ClickSetPosition
またもうひとつ ClickSetPosition というスクリプトが
attached to the environment.
背景にアタッチされています
The PropertiesAndCoroutines script has a
PropertiesAndCoroutines スクリプトは
public vector3 property called target
public Vector3 のプロパティ target を持ち
that encapsulates the target field.
これは target フィールドをカプセル化しています
Remember that when we allocate to the target
そして target プロパティを割り当てるときに
property we call the Set function.
set 関数を呼び出します
The ClickSetPositions script sets the target
これでシーン内の任意地点をクリックすると
of an object with the PropertiesAndCoroutine
ClickSetPositions スクリプトが PropertiesAndCoroutine スクリプトの
script on it to wherever we click in the environment.
アタッチされたオブジェクトの target をセットします
Back on the PropertiesAndCoroutines script
それでは PropertiesAndCoroutines スクリプトに戻って
let's see what happens when the target is set.
target がセットされた時に 何が起こるか見てみましょう
First we set the target field to the correct value.
まず target フィールドに正しい値がセットされます
Then we stop any movement coroutines.
そして移動のコルーチンを停止します
It is important to note the StopCoroutine
なお  これは次の行にも関係してきますが
only works with coroutines that have been started
StopCoroutine が動作するのはコルーチン名の
by the string call as we are on the next line.
文字列で呼び出して開始された場合だけです
This is the alternate way of calling StartCoroutine.
これは先ほど話した StartCoroutine を呼び出すもう一つのやり方です
We parse the name of the coroutine as a string
コルーチン名を文字列としてパースさせ
and then the parameter afterwards.
続けてパラメーターを指定します
Our movement coroutine is similar to the
続く Movement コルーチンの作りは
MyCoroutine from the last example.
先ほどの MyCoroutine と似ています
It simply lerps the cube's position towards
キューブの位置を指定された target に近づくように
a given target until it's close.
単純に線形補間（Lerp）しています
The effect of having our script setup like this is
このスクリプトの組み方だと
that we have a moving game object without the need
フレーム単位で値をポールする Update 関数を使うことなく
for an Update function that polls for a
移動するゲームオブジェクトを
values every frame.
作ることができます
Polling for a value is something that reduces the
値をポールする処理はコードの効率性を
efficiency of the code we write
下げるものですし
and while we sometimes have to,
どうしても必要な時を除けば
it is something we should try to avoid.
なるべく避けたい処理ですからね